In this video, we're finally going to give an actual bottom up parsing algorithm. In
在这段视频中，我们最终将给出一个实际的自下而上解析算法。在……里面
particular, we'll talk about SLR, or simple LR parsing, which will build on the
特别地，我们将讨论SLR，即简单的LR解析，它将构建在
ideas of valid items, and viable prefixes that we've been discussing in our recent
有效项目的概念，以及可行的前缀，这些都是我们在最近的
videos. The first thing we're going to do is to define a very weak bottom up parsing
视频。我们要做的第一件事是定义一个非常弱的自底向上解析
algorithm called LR0 parsing. And the basic idea here is that we're going to
称为LR0解析的算法。这里的基本想法是我们要
assume a stack contains a contents alpha, and that the next input is token T And
假设堆栈包含内容alpha，并且下一个输入是令牌T，并且
that the DFA, this is the DFA that recognizes, the viable prefixes. On input
DFA，这是识别可行前缀的DFA。在输入时
alpha, that is, when it reads the stack contents, it terminates in some state S.
也就是说，当它读取堆栈内容时，它在某个状态S终止。
[sound] And There's only gonna be two things that this that this parsing
[声音]这个解析只会有两件事
algorithm needs to do. So if S, if the final state of the DFA contains the item X
算法需要做的就是。所以如果S，如果DFA的最终状态包含项目X
goes to beta dot. Well, what does that say? That says we've seen the complete
转到贝塔点。那上面写的是什么？也就是说我们已经看到了完整的
right hand side, of X goes to beta on the top of the stack, and that furthermore,
右手边的X转到堆栈顶部的Beta，而且，
everything that's below the stack still says that x goes to beta dot is a valid,
堆栈下面的所有东西仍然说x到β点是有效的，
or a viable, sorry, is a valid item for this state. Meaning its okay to reduce by
或者一个可行的，抱歉，对于这个州来说是有效的项目。意思是可以减少
X goes to beta. So if we see a complete production dot all the way in the right
X转到贝塔。所以如果我们在右边看到一个完整的生产点
hand side in the final state of the DFA, then we're just going to reduce by that
在DFA的最终状态下，我们只需要减少它
production. The other possible move is a shift. If we wind up in a state, where, X
制作。另一个可能的举动是转变。如果我们最终到了一个州，在那里，X
goes to beta .t, and then some other stuff is a valid item, what does that say? That
转到测试版，然后其他一些东西是有效的，这是什么意思？那
says that it would be okay at this point to add a T to the stack. And if T is our
表示此时可以将T添加到堆栈中。如果T是我们的
input, well, then we should do a shift move [sound]. Now, when does LR0 parsing
输入，嗯，那么我们应该做一个换班动作[声音]。现在，LR0何时解析
get into trouble? Well, there are two possible problems it could have. It might
惹上麻烦了吗？嗯，它可能有两个可能的问题。它可能会
not be able to decide. Between two possible reduced moves. So, if any state
不能决定。在两个可能减少的动作之间。所以，如果有任何州
of DFA has two possible reductions, meaning it seem two complete productions
的DFA有两个可能的减少，这意味着它看起来像是两个完整的产品
and it could reduce by either one then there's not enough information to decide
它可以减少任何一个，那么就没有足够的信息来决定
which reduction to perform and the parts won't be completely deterministic, and
要执行哪种简化，并且各部分不是完全确定的，并且
this is called a reduced, reduced co nflict. So again, this happens if a
这被称为减少的冲突，减少的冲突。再说一次，如果一个
particular state has two separate items indicating two separate reductions. The
特定的州有两个单独的项目，表示两个单独的减少。这个
other possibility is that the final state of the DFA, after reading the stack
另一种可能性是在读取堆栈之后DFA的最终状态
contents, might have An item that says to reduce and another item that says to
内容，可能有一项说要减少，另一项说要
shift. And this is called a shift-reduce conflict. So in this case, there would
换档。这就是所谓的转移-减少冲突。所以在这种情况下，会有
only be a conflict in a state where T was the next item in the input. But in that
仅在T是输入中的下一项的状态下才是冲突。但在那里面
situation, we wouldn't know whether to shift T onto the stack, or to reduce by X
情况下，我们将不知道是将T移位到堆栈上，还是减去X
goes to beta [sound]. Let's take a look at the DFA for recognizing viable prefixes
转到测试版[声音]。让我们看一下识别可行前缀的DFA
that we've been using for the last couple of ideas, and in fact this particular DFA
我们在最后几个想法中一直在使用，实际上这个特定的DFA
does have some conflicts. So, let's take a look at this state right here, here we
确实有一些冲突。那么，让我们来看看这里的状态，这里我们
could either reduced by E goes to T you are in this state or if the next input is
是否可以减去E转到T，您处于此状态，或者如果下一个输入为
a plus we could do a shift and. In, so in this particular situation, if the next
A另外我们可以换班。在，所以在这个特殊的情况下，如果下一个
input is plus, we could either shift and use this item or we can reduce and use
投入是加的，我们可以移动并使用此项目，也可以减少并使用此项目
that item. So this particular state has a shift reduced conflict. Now, that's not
那件东西。因此，这个特殊的州减少了冲突。现在，那不是
the only conflict in this in this grammar, though. In this state here, we have a very
然而，在这个语法中，唯一的冲突就是这一点。在这个州，我们有一个非常
similar problem. Here we could shift if the next input is a times. Or we could
类似的问题。如果下一个输入是时间，我们可以在这里转换。或者我们可以
reduce by T goes to [inaudible]. And so this state also has a shift reduce
减去T表示[听不见]。所以这个状态也有一个移位减少
conflict. It turns out that it's not difficult to improve on LR0 parsing, and,
冲突。事实证明，改进LR0解析并不困难，
we'll present one such improvement in this video called SLR or simple LR parsing. And
在本视频中，我们将展示一个这样的改进，称为SLR或简单LR解析。和
this is going to improve on LR0 by adding some heuristics that will refine when we
这将通过添加一些启发式方法来改进LR0，这些启发式方法将在我们
shift and when we reduce, so that fewer states have conflicts. The modification to
当我们减少的时候，转移和减少，这样更少的国家会有冲突。修改为
LR0 parsing that gives us SLR parsing is really quite small. We just add one new
为我们提供SLR解析的LR0解析实际上相当小。我们只需添加一个新的
condition to the reduction case. So before, if we saw it, X goes to beta dot,
条件添加到减量案例中。所以在此之前，如果我们看到它，X会变成β点，
in the final state of our DFA, recall what that means. That means beta is on the top
在我们的DFA的最终状态中，回想一下这意味着什么。这意味着Beta版处于领先地位。
of the stack, and it is viable And so it's fine to reduce. Now, We do have a little
堆栈，它是可行的，所以减少是很好的。现在，我们确实有一些
bit more information. So, so notice that the automaton her e doesn't take any
更多信息。所以，请注意，她身上的自动机没有任何
advantage of what's coming up in the input. This is based entirely, this
利用输入中即将出现的内容。这完全是基于，这个
decision here is based entirely on the stack contents. But it might be that it
这里的决策完全基于堆栈内容。但可能是因为它
doesn't make sense to reduce based on what the next input symbol is. And how can we
根据下一个输入符号是什么来减去是没有意义的。我们怎么才能
take advantage of that? Well, if you think about it, what's going to happen? We have
利用这一点吗？嗯，如果你想一想，会发生什么呢？我们有
our stack contents. And, it ends in a beta, and now we're going to make a move
我们的堆栈内容。它以测试版结束，现在我们要采取行动
where we're going to replace that by X. Okay. And if the next input symbol is t,
我们要把它换成X，好的。并且如果下一个输入码元是t，
so remember we have a vertical bar here and a t following, what does that mean?
记住我们这里有一个竖线，后面跟着一个t，这是什么意思？
Well, that means that x has to come before t in the derivation. Or in another words,
这意味着在求导过程中，x必须在t之前。或者换句话说，
t is gonna follow x. And if t can't follow x, if t is a terminal symbol that can't
t会跟在x后面，如果t不能跟在x后面，如果t是一个不能跟在x后面的终端符号
come after the non-terminal x than it makes no sense to do this reduction. So we
紧跟在非终结点x之后，这样做是没有意义的。所以我们
only do the reduction if t is in the follow of x. We just add that restriction
只有当t在x的后面时才做减法。我们只是添加了这个限制
and that is the only change to the parsing algorithm. So if there are any conflicts
这是对解析算法的唯一更改。所以如果有任何冲突
under these rules either shift reduce or reduce, reduce, then the grammar is not an
在这些规则下，要么移位归约，要么归约，那么语法就不是
slr grammar. Just notice that these rules amount to a heuristic, for detecting the
SLR语法。只需注意，这些规则相当于一个启发式规则，用于检测
handles. So, we take into account two pieces of information. The contents of the
把手。因此，我们考虑了两条信息。文件中的内容
stack, that's that the DFA, does for us, and it tells us what items are possible
堆栈，这就是DFA为我们做的，它告诉我们哪些项是可能的
when we get to the top of the stack, and also what's coming up in input, and we can
当我们到达堆栈的顶部，以及输入中将要出现的内容时，我们可以
use that to define our reduction decisions. And for those grammars where
用它来定义我们的减排决定。对于那些语法来说，
there are no conflicts, meaning there is a, there is a unique move, in every
没有冲突，也就是说，每个人都有一种，有一种独特的举动。
possible state, under those rules. Then this heuristic is exact, you know, for,
可能的状态，在那些规则下。那么这个启发式是准确的，你知道，因为，
for those grammars. And we just define those grammars to be the SLR grammars.
对于那些语法来说。我们只是将这些文法定义为SLR文法。
Let's consider how things have changed for our running example. The deterministic
让我们考虑一下我们的运行示例的情况发生了怎样的变化。决定论
automaton for recognizing the viable prefixes of the grammar we've been looking
用于识别我们一直在寻找的语法的可行前缀的自动机
at for several videos now. Recall that we had shift reduced conflicts under LR zero
现在正在看几个录像带。回想一下，我们在LR为零的情况下减少了冲突
rules in two states. So now let's look at this state first, the upper state. So
有两个州的规定。现在让我们先来看看这个状态，上面的状态。所以
here, we 're going to shift if there's a plus in the input. That's what this item
这里，如果输入中有加号，我们就移动一下。这就是这个项目
tells us to do. It tells us there's if there's a plus, then the right move is to
告诉我们该做什么。它告诉我们，如果有加号，那么正确的做法是
shift. And so Now the question is, when are we going to reduce? Well we're only
换档。所以现在的问题是，我们什么时候减少呢？嗯，我们只是
going to reduce if the input is in the follow of E. And what is the follow of E?
如果输入跟在E后面就会减去，那么E跟在什么后面呢？
We computed that a long time ago, but just to remind you remember that E here is the
我们很久以前就计算过了，但我想提醒大家，这里的E是
original start symbol of the grammar so certainly dollar sign will wind up in the
语法的原始起始符号，所以美元符号肯定会出现在
follow of E. And the other possibility for the follow of E is close paren, because
跟在E后面的另一种可能性是接近Paren，因为
here at this point in the grammar close paren comes after E. And that's the only
在语法的这一点上，帕伦紧跟在E之后，这是唯一的
two possibilities. So what that says now, what that means is that, in this
有两种可能性。所以现在的意思是，在这件事上
particular state, we are going to reduce, if either we're out of input. Or if the
特定的州，我们将减少，如果我们没有输入的话。或者如果
next I, the next, token in the input is a closed paren, and will shift if the next
下一个I，下一个，输入中的令牌是一个闭合的Paren，如果下一个
token in the input is a plus. And in any other situation, we will report a parsing
输入中的标记为加号。在任何其他情况下，我们将报告解析
error. And so there's no longer any shift reduced conflict in this state, and
错误。因此，这个州不再有任何减少冲突的转变，而且
there's always a unique move for every possible input. The situation is
对于每一种可能的输入，总是有一个独特的动作。情况是这样的
similarly, similarly improved, for the other state. So here, we're going to shift
同样，对于另一个州，也有类似的改进。所以在这里，我们要把
in there's a times in the input, and we're going to reduce if the input is in the
在输入中有一个次数，如果输入在
follow of T. And what is the follow of T? [sound]. Recall, We computed this again a
T的后边是什么？T的后边是什么？[声音]。回想一下，我们再次将其计算为
long time ago and I just happen to know what it is. And so I'll just tell you.
很久以前，我正好知道那是什么。所以我就直接告诉你。
Well it included everything in the follow of e. So a dollar sign in close paren are
它包含了跟在e后面的所有东西。所以在Close Paren中有一个美元符号
in the follow of T. But also, a plus is in the follow of T because of this usage over
在T的后面，加号也在T的后面，因为这种用法是Over
here in the grammar where plus appears really after T. But those are the only
在语法中，加号确实出现在T之后，但这是唯一的
things in the follow of T. And so now we're going to reduce, only if we're out
紧跟在T后面的东西，所以现在我们要减少，只有当我们退出的时候
of input or if the next input item is a close paren or a plus and there's also a
或者如果下一个输入项是接近的Paren或加号，并且还有
no shift reduce, no longer any shift reduce conflict in this state. And so this
在这种状态下，没有减速，不再有减速冲突。所以这就是这个
grammar, is an SLR1 grammar. Now many grammars are not SLR. To emphasize that
语法，是一种SLR1语法。现在很多语法都不是SLR。强调一下，
SLR is an improvement on LR0 but it 's still, not a really very general class of
单反是对lr0的改进，但它仍然不是一个真正非常通用的类。
grammars. So All ambiguous grammars for example are not SLR. We can improve a
语法。因此，例如，并不是所有的歧义语法都是SLR。我们可以改进一个
little bit on the SLR situation. We can make SLR parsers even more grammarous, by
关于单反的情况。我们可以通过以下方式使SLR解析器更加文法
using precedence declarations to tell it how to resolve conflicts. So let's revert
使用优先级声明告诉它如何解决冲突。所以让我们恢复原状
to the most natural and also most ambiguous grammar for plus and times over
到最自然也最模棱两可的加号和倍数语法
the integers, and we've looked at this grammar before. If you build the DFA for
整数，我们以前已经看过这个语法了。如果您为以下对象构建DFA
this grammar, if you go through and build the DFA for the viable prefix of this
这个语法，如果您通读并为它的可行前缀构建DFA
grammar, you will discover that there is a state. That has the following two items in
语法，你会发现有一种状态。中包含以下两项的
it, one says that if we see E times E that we have seen E times E on a stack, and
它，有人说，如果我们看到E乘以E，那就是我们在堆栈上看到了E乘以E，
that we can now reduce by ecos E times E. The other one will say that if there's a
我们现在可以减去Ecos E乘以E，另一个人会说如果有一个
plus coming up in the input we should shift. And notice that this is exactly the
再加上，在输入端，我们应该移一下。请注意，这正是
question. Of whether, times has higher precedence than plus. When you're in this
问题来了。是否，乘以比加优先。当你在这里的时候
situation, should you. Reduce, thereby grouping the two E's together here,
情况，你应该。减去，从而将两个E组合在一起，
Grouping the multiplication operation first. Or should you shift the plus, in
首先对乘法运算进行分组。或者您应该将加号移入
which case you'll be working on that for a sentence at the top of the stack. So, in
在这种情况下，您将为堆栈顶部的句子处理此问题。所以，在
this situation, the declaration times has higher precedence than plus resolves the
在这种情况下，声明时间的优先级高于加来解决
conflict in favor of the reduction. So we would not do the shift, and we would wind
支持削减的冲突。所以我们不会换班，我们会上发条
up with no shift-reduce conflict. Note that the term precedence declaration is
没有换挡-减少冲突。请注意，术语优先声明是
actually quite misleading. These declarations don't define precedence. They
实际上相当具有误导性。这些声明不定义优先级。他们
don't. Do that directly at all. What they really define are conflict resolution.
不要。完全可以直接这么做。他们真正定义的是冲突解决。
They say, make this move instead of that move. It happens that in this particular
他们说，做这个动作而不是那个动作。碰巧在这个特殊的地方
case. Because we're dealing with a national grammar, simple grammar for plus
箱子。因为我们处理的是一种全国性的语法，简单的加号语法
and times that the conflict resolution has exactly the effect of enforcing the
以及冲突解决恰好具有强制
precedence declaration that we want. But in more complicated grammars where there
我们想要的优先声明。但在更复杂的语法中
are more interactions between various pieces of the grammar, these declarations
在语法的不同部分之间有更多的交互，这些声明
might not do what you expect in terms of enforcing precedence, fortuna tely, you
可能不会按照您期望的那样执行优先顺序，幸运的是，您
can always print out the automaton. The tools provide, Usually a way for you to
可以随时打印出机器人。这些工具通常为您提供了一种
inspect the parsing automaton. And then you can see exactly how, the conflicts are
检查解析自动机。然后你就可以确切地看到，冲突是如何
being resolved, and whether those are the resolutions that you had intended. And I
正在解决中，以及这些是否是您原本想要的解决方案。而我
recommend when you're building parsers, especially if it's a, a fairly complex
建议您在构建解析器时，尤其是在解析器相当复杂的情况下
parser, that you do examine the parsing automaton to make sure that it's doing
解析器，即检查解析自动机以确保它正在执行
what you expect. So now we're ready to give the algorithm for SLR parsing. So
如你所料。现在我们准备给出SLR解析的算法。所以
[inaudible] automaton, our parsing automaton that recognizes viable prefixes.
[听不见]自动机，我们的解析自动机可以识别可行的前缀。
The initial configuration is going to be with the vertical bar all the way to the
初始配置将使用竖线一直到
left so the stack is empty. This is our full input and we [inaudible] dollar to
向左，因此堆栈为空。这是我们的全部投入，我们[听不见]美元
indicate the end of the input. And now we're going to repeat until the
指示输入的末尾。现在我们要重复，直到
configuration has just the start symbol on the stack, and dollar in the input.
配置在堆栈上只有开始符号，在输入中有美元。
Meaning all the input is gone and we've reduced the entire input to the start
这意味着所有的输入都消失了，我们从一开始就减少了整个输入
symbol. So. An [inaudible] configuration will be written as alpha-omega; where
符号。所以。[听不见]配置将写为alpha-omega；其中
alpha is the contents of the stack and omega is the remaining input, and what
alpha是堆栈的内容，omega是剩余的输入，还有什么
we're going to do is we're going to run M, run the machine on the current stack alpha
我们要做的是运行M，在当前堆栈alpha上运行机器
and if M rejects alpha, if M says that alpha is not a viable prefix, then we're
如果M拒绝Alpha，如果M说Alpha不是可行的前缀，那么我们就
going to report a parsing error. We're gonna stop right there. Now, if M accepts
将报告解析错误。我们就到此为止吧。现在，如果M接受
alpha, and it accepts it in a state, if it ends in a state with items I, then we're
Alpha，它在一种状态下接受它，如果它以包含项i的状态结束，那么我们
gonna look at the next input, call that A, and what are we going to do? Well, we're
看下一个输入，称它为A，然后我们要做什么？嗯，我们正在
going to shift. Yes, there's an item. In I that says, it would be okay to see the
我要换班了。是的，有一样东西。在我说的话里，可以看到
terminal A. Next. Okay? So that's just our shift move. And then we're going to reduce
A航站楼。下一个。好吧?所以这只是我们的换班动作。然后我们将减少
if there's a reduction item, in the in the set of valid items. And the next input can
如果存在缩减项，则在有效项集中的。并且下一个输入可以
follow the non-terminal on the left hand side. So these are just the two rules that
沿着左手边的非终点站行驶。所以这只是两条规则，
we discussed before. And then we'll report a parsing error if neither of these
我们之前讨论过。然后，如果这两个都不是，我们将报告解析错误
applies. Okay, now one interesting thing about this algorithm, if you read it
适用。好的，现在关于这个算法有一件有趣的事，如果你读了它
carefully and you th ink about it for awhile. You'll realize that this step is
仔细考虑一下，你再想一想这件事。你会意识到这一步是
actually not needed, that we don't need to check here For whether M accepts the
实际上不需要，我们不需要在这里检查M是否接受
stack, or not. Because this staff down here, where we report a parsing error, if
堆叠，或不堆叠。因为下面这位员工，我们报告了一个解析错误，如果
neither of these steps applies, this already implies that we will never form an
这两个步骤都不适用，这已经意味着我们永远不会形成
invalid stack, That our, their stacks will always be viable. The parsing errors will
无效的堆栈，那就是我们的，他们的堆栈永远是可行的。解析错误将
be caught at this line, and we won't pollute the stack with symbols that can't
在这一行被抓到，我们就不会用不可能的符号污染堆栈
possibly result in viable prefixes. So in fact, this error check here, is not
可能会产生可行的前缀。所以实际上，这里的错误检查并不是
needed, M is always going to accept the stack. If there are any conflicts in the
需要时，M将始终接受堆栈。如果
last step, meaning, it's not clear whether to shift or reduce in some state for some,
最后一步，也就是说，对于一些人来说，不清楚是在某种状态下转移还是减少，
input symbol, then the grammar is not, SLRK. And K, again, is the amount of look
输入符号，则语法为NOT，SLRK。再说一次，K是看的量
ahead. In practice, we just use one token of look ahead, So typically, just looking
往前走。在实践中，我们只使用一个向前看的标记，所以通常情况下，只是看
at the next token in the input stream.
在输入流中的下一个令牌。